All right. Hello everyone. Welcome. I'm
going to begin this stream with a GitHub
push to the Octave Inference Institute
GitHub account no.org. So start this big
push and then we are going to be in the
game. All right. First, where we're
headed, we are going to be designing
cars for butterflies. And we're going to
be doing that by orchestrating a ton of
different kinds of different agents, LLM
and otherwise. It's actually even a lot
more general than that. So, stick
around, find out, and if you're in the
live chat, looking forward to your
comments and questions. So, let's pull
back a second. This is Active Infinance
Stream
13.1. It's April 25th, 2025. I'm Daniel
Freriedman and the title of this stream
is no or is a real or let us confirm
that GitHub is still pushing. We'll
reload it soon. All right. Big picture.
This is part of some ongoing projects
that are related to organizations
documentation and multi-agent systems.
This is open- source
CCPsa 4.0.
Now that the GitHub push has come
through, we will reload the repo which
was empty up until
now and we see everything there. So let
us start with looking at the outputs
from the example. So where are we headed
here? We're headed into extremely
flexible, bottomup, vibecoded,
open-source, customizable, multi-agent
orchestration using an enormous
repository of different documents and
templates and
tools. Um, as just one example, and I
will look forward to people suggesting
more examples in the chat, and we'll do
a bunch of them. Where this is going to
go is in the example number eight.
At the top of the script is the convict.
So this was about designing an
eco-friendly transportation solution for
pollinators to design a lightweight
vehicle was the objective. There were
some constraints related to toxicity and
the target users are butterflies
actually but conservation organizations
as well. So just to sort of confirm
this, I'll wait until somebody makes a
suggestion and then I will modify the
project config to be whatever other
inventive scenario we want. And where
that takes us is we get a few different
visualizations. So here's a
visualization of the whole workflow.
First, the research unit does
requirements analysis through LLM.
send some messages out to the
development unit, out to the community
engagement unit, budget allocation, all
these different rule-based and LLM based
agents that are sending messages to and
from each other. And that ends up
getting uh okay by board. There's a
bunch of different steps. We'll have
different examples. And then finally, it
results in the marketing department
doing some calls to some image
generation services for what the final
product might look like. So we can kind
of pick um what type of organizational
structure and flow we want and that is
no or. So we will return to how the
example works in a little bit more
detail. First going to
noorg.g. Again, anyone who writes a
comment or an idea or a question in the
chat, I will try to incorporate this.
Okay. Why no? No. Or is not an
organization. It's a metaorganization. A
way of thinking about how organizations
work. It is like cognition is to
organization as metacognition is to no
org. And that draws a lot from metagove.
And that's going to come into play later
in the stream. So part one, no org is
not a real organization. It's not an
organization. It is a template and a
grammar and system for organizations.
Kind of like how metacognition is about
punch.
But at the same time, no or if you break
it up a little differently, not that
it's not an organization, but N O
knowledge as in new meets RG, which
could be reormalization group, it could
be role playing game. And it is a real
org. This isn't just theory. No org is a
functioning entity, a living system
where different kinds of interaction
generate tangible outcomes and
structure. The no acknowledges the
unconventional, the emergent, the
resistance to rigid definition, yet
affirms its genuine existence and
operational reality. Or as they say, no
organization, no organization, no
organization, no
organization. And this is not an
organization yet. And perhaps it
functions just as one. So after all, was
it a real
organization? People talk a lot about
agents and agents in organizations.
However, at the tactical and the
operational level, this is coming down
to among other things documentation,
structure and process flows. We are at a
point where with the qualitative
understanding of this and the above plus
a little bit of vibe coding it is
possible to develop some groundup
software packages and paradigms for
flexible design development and
deployment of agents in an open-source
fashion that is agnostic of
implementation structure function and
process
flow. Knowledge is relational. The unit
paradox we will look at the units. Here
is a quick look at the Obsidian
documentation graph of what the unit
structure looks like. So when you
dispatch those
messages, think about these units and
all that they have to do. Here's here's
operations unit, one of the core units.
And here's all of the documents that are
connected to this
massive well ststructured at least in
theory units repository. We're going to
get there.
What is a unit? What is nation? What is
a tool? What is a finite? What is an
infinite game? How do we play? How does
the map redraw itself? How do we diagram
out these different kinds of units and
functionalities? How do we explore
pattern over prescription and seek an
emergent order? How do we come to
understand that knowledge lives in
practice? And this fundamental paradox
of the empty center, the donor,
Taurus, where and how do duality and
recursion come into play when thinking
about the sacred geometries of
organization of living systems? How can
we use different kinds of interactivity
to have this holistic sinthetic
understanding of structure for cyber
physical systems? And where does that
take us in terms of a coonl like
understanding of
structure? Let us go to the
examples after briefly looking at what
the units are. So here is a
obsidian representation graphical view
of these different repos.
we will go into the charter of the
finance unit. So here we are looking at
it in obsidian and here it is in
cursor. So these are all files and
there's a different amount in in
different ones of them but they all have
some core files like the charter the
index etc. Let's go to
education. So here's the charter of
education and it's written out in plain
text and what that looks like in cursor
in the education charter is these double
bracketed links. So this is how obsidian
knows that it is in an obsidian
knowledge base and that gets rendered
out like this.
So education charter index of different
documents within the education unit and
this can go to an arbitrary level of
detail. So let's just start up a
new chat over
here. Drag over
education in the education
unit. Comprehensively add sections and
documents.
for everything
a education unit.
So we'll let that process and the idea
with this is they are human readable and
there's ways to render in and out of
obsidian knowledge bases but human
readable forms that give these semantic
interfaces that are going to come into
play in several ways. So at one level
just by having
these files in the cursor repo when we
then go and code something else
somewhere else using prompt engineering
then it's going to find some of this
information relevance. So that's a very
qualitative semantic proximity based
approach. Like if we were going to go
over to some folder and say write an
education paradigm and then in the
education folder there's already a
curriculum and there's already these
different kinds of things like AI
principles curriculum. So education
could host different information on
initiatives, their their performance
indications, different meeting notes
that they've had within subgroups or
different teams within their unit. So
this is like an organizational structure
and all of that
is linked up in
the unit directory. So here's the big
picture of the unit. This is just one
way to draw it out. So high level
structure here's different
organizational relationships. Let's look
at it in GitHub
units units are
out. So in GitHub the double brackets
don't render like they do in Obsidian.
It's still there though. Still plain
text. Part of the beauty of plain
text. Organizational structure almost
cool. It's like it's redacted. It's like
it doesn't really matter which one they
specifically are, but you can have
detailed relationships with executive
knowledge, corporate, infra, ops,
product, tech,
revenue, different templates and
paradigms for strategy, tactics and
operations, different information
flow, different unit structure and the
way that those link up. And then the
dense linking in the hypertext and in
the obsidian form tables of information
interfaces with different
communities cross
functionality. These can get spun out to
the M degree and they have all kinds of
information that is both at this
uh kind of
representation totally readable
representable screenshotable by people
also plain text versionable like you can
version it in GitHub that's what we're
going to be doing a lot of and then also
it can be used for machine
interpretability legibility of of
documentation
and all of these different kinds of
features. So here is what's called 3.7
chugging away in the education
unit. So here is updates
[Music]
happening updates happening in the
education unit. So
it enhanced the read
me made a new structure for the
curriculum. Now it's just writing and
chugging along writing different
materials for the education. We can add
all all kinds of features
there. So this project started as
thinking well how how can we generalize
across organizational structures? How
can we here we are in the
units. How can we look at different
units and frame the relationship very
generically? Kind of like a Linux
kernel. The Linux distribution is not
necessarily set up with your username
and your password and your wallpaper.
There might be some defaults or it might
just be a placeholder. But then this can
be rendered or deployed kind of like
again a Linux kernel for
organizations. Um, and it's an
opportunity to flesh out some really
exciting and interesting things in this
generic. So here's another example of
that. Within the security department, we
have cognitive security, digital
security, and physical security. Of
course, cognitive being the most general
of them all. And there's only a few
documents in here now. But we can start
to play
around in the security
unit. Oh, wait a minute. No, no playing
in the security unit and start to
explore what does that generic framework
for security in an organization look
like? And it's like as always the
generic and the specific, right? genus
and species generalizations and linear
particulars. So we might draw and abduct
or induct or deduct in different ways
thinking about like this would be super
cool for a research unit in general.
What would be their focus areas in
general? Or there could be a subress
research area like it could be the taste
research unit. So these kind of nested
and interacting units give a lot of
opportunity to take the generalization
right up to and probably a little bit
beyond the point of being generic and
end up with all of these different uh
kinds of sub and fractal and nested
interacting structures. So we will add a
education subunit for
language learning be
comprehensive be
comprehensively okay so that's kind of
the unit structure and I believe that
that is some of the utility and novelty
in this situation which is that it's an
obsidian open- source plain text
approach
to
representing organizational structures
in in the generic and in the specific
case
using Obsidian as a way to visualize
this no org, right? Because it's not an
organization. So all these different
connections and and people can look at
how different things connect up and
there's the unit directory, all the
things that it's connected and and
draws.
Okay. So that is the unit component of
this
package. Push the GitHub
update.
Okay. Okay. back to the uh screen agenda
which I'll just break down as we get
through things. So the
unit directory and the markdown
relationships was what I began with was
building this out and just continuing to
say okay now add a new unit now add this
unit now link these two units now add
this unit now add more within this unit
just what other units would be relevant
just keeping going and going at all
those different uh meta organizational
meta governance type structures let's
add a department of metad
What?
What's in units? Make a new unit with
all needed documents
and for
meta
documents
about fractal and scale
three
and interacting.
governance processes within
and language learning
subunit. We have a language learning
folder. It's been one of the most
effective augmenters of VI coding has
been first off the multi-shot agent mode
in cursor and then improved ability to
have situational awareness in the file
structure and being able to have new
folders get made and
uh make files iteratively all that kind
of
stuff plugging away on the language
learning education unit is in process.
Okay. So the units folder it's again
it's
uh pretty simple in concept and it can
get rolled out to basically the nth
degree of sophistication. You can get as
many generic or specific policies as you
want. Just keep going. You can continue
to uh work off of the org chart, metaorg
chart/module structure that is currently
in the no org repo or I think you've
probably seen enough even at this point
just to go into cursor or whatever and
just say okay build me a modular meta
organizational structure roll out every
single possible thing that could be
relevant for XY and that that'll kind of
build you what you not at the right
level of detail and and you know tuning
and tweaking along the
way. Okay, back to
the again. Third time to return to this.
But I started with just the Obsidian
repo. There was no code in this repo at
all. It was just about well if you
consider what you consider a code what
you consider a code
uh only in the units repo
uh just exploring and I thought okay
well wouldn't it be pretty cool to be
able to start to deploy custom
configurations of agents within those
units and that is where it went. So
there's a few different other folders to
look at. Agents has a lot of
information. All of these documents,
ridiculous numbers of documents. So
here, this Obsidian window is only
looking at the
units. Now, this one is pulled out to
the broader
no.org. So they're both kind of mutating
as the metaggo files come into
play. So here's the broader
organization.
slightly different, much larger
um network, lot of more standalone files
because uh outside of the units
directory, there's less obsidian
linking here in the uh agents again top
level folder. There's all these
documents
and ranging from the these some of these
are obsidian link. They're they're more
heterogeneous. Let's look at it
in let's
see. So this is like why putting stuff
online makes a semantic impact even if
it's hard to get attention of people in
the moment. It's like all the work that
Metagod and people using the term have
done, some of it gets slurped up, used
as training data and that supports later
through this kind of airlock of not
really citing them. Sometimes a specific
citation or URL or person might pop up,
but it's uh using the semantics of how
meta governance was discussed by the
people who discussed it. That's how
symbols and words work. So here's a
charter for a meta meta governance unit.
And then if people want to configure
their own
organization as opposed to this
non-existence organization that we keep
on talking about with without this or
with it, you can have knowledge
management. You can have a legal
department or or not. But it's
configurable. That's kind of the cool
thing. Okay, back to looking at the
agents
in let's
see it's a lot of there there's some
code in the agents folder but not not
not that much of that here are a large
number of agentic
semantic coding. So this is like at the
meta agent implementation level all
these different kinds
of schema
uh just at the conceptual level like if
we want to talk about how do we tune
performance in multi- aent
systems just some pseudo
code some different ideas some different
patterns how do we think about
autonomous learning
How do we think about learning
architectures, learning
systems, different ways? It could be
pseudo code. But this is not meant to be
executable directly. But again, where's
all of where's all this going with the V
code? Natural language is code code
along all that. And so these kinds of
plain text which are now happily
publicly available
in this open source repo it it plays a
role. So if someone says change tracking
and make new changes yellow, that's
going to move the needle in some little
way into who knows how long later and
someone says make a visualization for
change tracking and that yellow is going
to put its little syntactic finger on
the scale. So that's what's happening in
the system agent system folder is
different kinds of looser semantics
using natural language. But again,
heavily human interpretable and heavily
machine readable for all these kinds of
qualitative interpretable elements of
agents. There are guides, just a few of
them, but they are guides to different
situations where you might want to do
aation line. So, here's like a swarm
implementation. Some of this refers to
some real code, some of it doesn't, but
the whole point. And what we see is you
just say, "Okay, build it out where it's
missing. Use this pattern and and go
from there." And that will basically get
you where you need to go. So
guides,
examples. Let's look at it in both
places. Here are again markdown files of
different examples of multi-agent
behavior. So part of it is like why why
state the office? But it it gives it if
you want to just say go to the continent
or go to this region or go to this city
block or go to this nanometer. There's
multiple levels of semantic precision
and it's not that more is simply better.
So actually having a really elegant
small concise way to be like when we
talk about task execution behavior
here's broadly what we're talking about.
We mean that this is what happens or
when we talk about learning this is what
we mean. Those are helpful and then more
technical details can always be
scaffolded and layered in. Maybe there's
programming languages, coding agents,
all this kind of stuff we don't even
know about. I would highly believe that.
So why not work at a level like a meta
organizational level or a meta
programming language level or a metal
linguistic level that can always be
deployed in different ways. What do we
mean by coordination behavior?
uh in the communication
folder just a few documents about
communication specifically. It's like
you can keep on growing these documents
and then it's okay now let's have a
subfolder for just monitoring. Let's
have a subfolder for just task
execution. Keep on growing out and and
watering and improving these documents
and modifying them as they go. and
architectures which give a few documents
that are related to architectural
concepts in agent design like cognitive
models. So the next time that there's a
new paper or a new new social media post
or some other kind of cognitive model,
it can just get plugged right in here.
So it's kind of like a new restaurant
opening in a region. it can already be
linked in to what is the region, what is
the kind of food, it's a restaurant, all
these background pieces of information
that already bring it into this very
interoperable system. So that's the
agent archive has a few different uh
prior tests. Let's see if any of them
are relevant.
This one
was a multi- aent sorting algorithm just
using this swarm dispatch paradigm to to
do some sorting on different
uh numbers.
This one was a test suite that was
written to do a lot of the functional
testing for
uh multi- aent systems. So looking at
task
performances and then it got up to doing
the towers of Hanoi. So this is
like a a team of agents that were spun
up and spun
down that
were playing this
towers. So people see
that that's in the archive. All right.
Then there's
dist. So this was another uh approach to
writing out different kinds of
multi-agent systems.
different ways. There's multiple
different frameworks. Obviously, that
would be saying least that there's many
different ways to do multiation
modeling. So, so these are just showing
that there's a few different ways to
have in this case JavaScript agents that
have different kinds of capacities,
different kinds of abilities that could
be augmented or or the semantics could
be transferred to all different kinds of
settings. That's the
disc. And this is a
uh uh message passing
architecture that that actually does
have some function, but it's not the
main one. And uh last before we get to
the examples of this TypeScript code is
the docs folder, the metadox, the
paradox, the the docs of docs. Here is
is a um vast number of folders of
documents that some of them have a ton
of information, some of them have just a
little bit of information and they are
just another way to include semantics
related to these topics. Pretty
interesting to think about like where
and how is the folder structure just the
regular computer nested folder structure
sufficient for conveying the kinds of
structural and
infrastructural and superstructural
information that we want to
convey and where do we want to use like
graphical databases other methods. So,
we won't look through all these
documents, of course, but they're all up
there and they come into play when you
use
curso carefully, then continue to add
links and relevant metag stuff.
So the docs folder
has all different kinds of relevant
documentation that can be brought into
play in in different ways. So it can
again be used at that qualitative level
of just like here
is AGI safety. Well, then if you type in
something related to that or something
happens related to that, then whatever
is in this file is going to come into
more play than it would have otherwise.
Uh there is a bunch of sections. Uh
let's see if there's any other ones.
Poor documentation. That's the
documentation on the documentation on
the documentation. Different ways to do
automation.
The git is actually a real one. Fractic
git is a fractal
git
program. So just tucking away. It's kind
of like you're looking through a
library, a hyper library of
documentation and sometimes there's a
little bookmark, sometimes there's a
little pheromone trail. Other times it's
like, huh, that's a whole functional
piece of software. So in this case, the
fractit
system as inspired by proof of course is
a
fractal git coordinator that spins up
and down and makes different kinds of
git operations on a fractal git
structure. So that kind of extends the
git concept to these nested quantum
superpositional
repos. But it could be anything. But it
it actually does have some utility. So
being able to make
repos spin up, spin down, clone, merge,
all those different kinds of operations
on fractal git operations. You give a
lot of flexibility because again though
it's probably or possibly not the most
high bandwidth or or high utility
representation structure to use the
computer nesting system. And even though
it might not be the exact set of
commands that are the most useful in all
possible universes like the default
Linux ones, there's a ridiculous amount
of training data on these kinds of
things. So using folder structures and
git play text you can get really far and
do a lot. So metagove still chugging
away.
see if there's any
other types of documentation that
are different uh
integrations with messaging platforms or
could get integrated to uh matter most
matter bridge be able to to bridge
across different messaging
platforms some related sections to the
units lot of maintenance information. So
what what at this meta documentational
level what are
good documentation maintenance practices
that can be specified whether you're
talking about documentation for building
a car, driving a
car, whatever it is. this is the meta
all of that and then today or tomorrow
you can send a person undergrad code
agent whatever and say go to the
maintenance folder and do da da da and
all all of that screenshot
management we've been in some situations
where the the proven screenshot was was
make or break it was sink or swim so
having the screenshot management on
point it's like I've never seen it
written out that way, but I could see
why it matters once it was written out a
way. Meta documentation in the meta
documentation is actually quite a large
section with information
on the information on structure and
information helping provide some meta
documentation on this docs folder.
different metrics. So then when a prompt
is used like make it secure or make it
high quality or make it performance
those can be just filled up with the
make it
successful, make it valuable. Those are
going to be just drawing on the base
semantic distribution of whatever model
you use plus whatever indirect context
you have in the codebase or scope plus
whatever are in these
documents. So if you super emphasize
that quality means elegance then that is
going to move the needle in that
direction. Let's just see if there's any
other then we'll go to the examples.
user interface troubleshooting
training. Just open these up, see what's
there, and then we will close Obsidian
and work more with the code examples,
get back to that butterfly call. So
meanwhile, if anyone watching has a
suggestion for a
uh a
uh something that they want invented
through this multi- aent orchestration
or a new setting, then check. Yeah,
prompts. This is just kind of there's
there's a lot of ways to do prompt
management of course, but here the
prompt folder. So then when when you
write a prompt or even
not do good knowledge
management and as as usual mermaid
diagrams coming in super
clutch very few tokens so very easy to
make a difference on a text model and it
renders plain text etc for for high
information throughput for for people
and for visual
Accessibility promps
folder quality assurance research search
security different security concepts
different ways to to discuss it setting
up software
standards
strategies systems system
science more
systems
templates I mean I it just it it is kind
of like just to continue to play out.
What does it look like when we keep on
nesting templates like okay well we
could have templates about meeting notes
so that you can get into more and more
levels of detail with templates
on on just more and more and
more or not just use the base
probabilistic distribution of the
language model. But if a template is in
place, you can investigate it and it
it testing tools
training troubleshoot. All right, that
will be it for the Obsidian
part and we will look
now at
the at where we got here. Okay. So, I'm
going to focus on
the experiment number
eight and
nine. Eight is going to be a uh 7, 8,
and 9 are are uh some of the more
uh sophisticated ones.
seven is uh and and all this goes into
the output
folder. Oh, all the the source code for
all of these examples is in SRC. So
here's where there's a ton of
information, utilities,
uh there's a documentation folder inside
of SRC, of course, core methods,
different monitoring, messaging,
different patterns, different
typescripts,
uh and some agent types, which can be up
to the we'll probably not go too deep
into SRC, but let's look at the examples
now.
Uh so in the multi- unit LLM flow seven
which will just kind of pass through
because
uh eight is a little bit bigger. So in
this
case this
[Music]
up. So here's this was an orchestrated
flow. the these things are going to
happen in this
order
and this is the summary of of what
happened. So the the the initial prompt
that was given to the to the innovation
unit was uh a machine for counting and
behavior and then this cost it looks
like 67 cents. Not not sure if that was
accurate. Probably less than that. Um
and that summarizes the entire process.
uh it is first sent from the innovation
needed to assess the idea then the the
the uh generation of ideas. So here's
the idea generation response. But we'll
we'll look at this in. So prompt is a
fixed
prompt and then it gets
back. Okay, here's ant scope, ant
monitor. Here's different ideas. Ants
site, ant secure, ant
connect that gets sent, the idea
generation gets sent to the market
research security assessment and then
finally to the board of review. So let's
look at the board
review. The ANSCO project aligns well
with our organization's strategic focus
on using technology to address
environmental concerns etc
etc that is then refined with feedback
at the innovation unit. There's a
technical and a brand planning and then
finally the final project plan is
written out. So all of this was just
autonomously orchestrated based on this
fixed organization topology. So final
project
plan, it's an executive
summary with all of the information from
the different
sections. So that's seven, example
seven, the multi-unit flow. Okay, eight
is the the one that uh is brings in a
few other features.
All
right. You see
person? Okay.
Uh so as shown a little bit earlier what
this script is going to do is
demonstrate combining multiple agent
types in a single workflow. There are
some LLM calls there are some rulebased
systems and there's also image
generation with different kinds of
coordinations. So let
us modify this section. Well, first
anyone watching live, write your idea
for a project or the context for a
project and meanwhile we'll just look at
the butterfly car design to look at
where we're going to get which is all
the intermediates are safe. So here's
like the architecture designer. The the
system prompt is you're a systems
architect system generic prompt. And
then the user prompt is design a
lightweight aerodynamic vehicle
optimized for butterfly transportation
in sync. And then the output from the
architecture designer is this is what
this is the concept. It's in adjacent so
it's wide but it it it feels worthy now
having GDPR for
butterflies using different kinds of
access control and encryption
for the um images
folder are where the final prompts are
created and then sent out. So here's
like the butterfly card, here's a logo
and here's a systems representation.
So let us uh make
another
concept just to confirm that it's doing
it from
scratch using control K just to modify
it in line. This is also quite long
file. This is over 3,000 lines of
code. All right.
the update this. So it
is designing a
physical
crypto
currency hardware
wallet that must be
invisible and
waterproof
for children.
So now it's called stealth kids crypto
warm and all I prompted here using the
cursor was prompting to change these
projects. So it could be different
domain, could be different user group,
different constraints. You know, it has
to cost $0 or whatever it is. Then
over on the right hand
side, I'm going to just ask cursor to
run
8. So it will generate up the codes
running. All right. So meanwhile, while
Walt 8 is running over there, we're
going to look at the
um example
N. All right. So, example nine, here's
where the uh output is going to get to.
So this is the executive
summary. This report presents the
results of an active inference partially
observable composition process model
used to analyze temperature changes
throughout a narrative. The model was
designed to extract temperature
information from the story and determine
optimal actions based on the inferred
states in the environment.
So, this has information
on
this. Let's put that
here. So, here's beliefs belief updating
about
temperature. Some of these can can be
fleshed out. Um, but the way that this
one works is that a story is defined in
natural language in the
prompt and then first an LLM is going to
be called to say what do you think the
temperature was at each beginning,
middle and end of the story and then the
outputs of that structured outputs from
that LLM
end up getting taken as observations for
a palm DP that then runs an active
inference algorithm.
So this uh is uh more of just a two-step
uh
program eight running in the background.
So this one let's also do a little
modification.
So here in this story it was crisp in
the morning then the sun was high. So
it's kind of indirectly saying it was it
was the weather was perfect for hiking
neither too hot nor too cold but in the
morning it was quite
cold outside the temperature continued
to drop. So, it kind of went from like
medium to cold, from from cold to medium
to very
cold. Right. A new
story about an
egg crying as
the in the room
changes. Okay, so eight is running over
there on the sideline.
And so you can
uh
Oh,
interesting. Interesting
story. Let's here just run.
There's some document chunking and
splitting
techniques. So here we are looking at
output. Did we save
it? Okay. Oh, it's still working in the
butterfly situation. This is another
another
freshly another a different butterfly.
Wow. It's like a spaceship full of
butterflies just like it should
be. And we'll see the third one just
appear.
Butterfly. All
right. It's just cuz I didn't save it.
Not
saved. Great. We just changed the
part
again. So that that'll show up in the
folder as Stealth Kids crypto wallet.
Okay, while that's
going. All right, we did the GitHub
push. We looked at the outputs from the
examples. We looked at the butterfly car
design and now we're making the stealth
crypto kids
model. Looked over the sections of no or
this is not an organization. You know
what is it? Reviewed the unit meta
architecture. talked about the
documentation. All right, there's two
more sections that
uh few more sections. First, I'm going
to look at cognitism by my colleague
John Ash and explore what happens when
we input the concepts of cognitism into
this framework. Then we will go to
Metag and pick one of their projects,
possibly the
Constitutions, possibly a living
manifesto for online spaces and and see
where that goes in this no org set and
then look at any comments in the live
chat and like if somebody wants to
suggest another cool product to design
or or some other funny thing. So here's
now here's new active
output. So let's look at this
report.
Okay. Similar
think people get it. Uh this is a very
useful pattern though what's happening
in nine which is taking in natural
language and then having LLM do some
kind of inference on it like tell me how
many characters are in the story or how
many facts support this versus how many
facts support that or what temperature
do you think it is or how much do you
think that would have cost all those
kinds of questions. Not that it
necessarily returns an accurate
understanding, but first off, you can
sample it a bunch of times at different
temperatures, and that enables you to
get a really good inference on the lat
space of the LLM. So, you can say, what
GPS coordinate do you
think this picture is taken at? And so
you can resample that a bunch of times
to get the underlying distribution of
its beliefs about the GPS locations of
that prompt given the context. And that
doesn't mean it's accurate, but it does
mean that you have made an accurate
measurement of that probabilistic
system. Okay. Now, now we're outputting
the folder stealth kids crypto wallet.
So let's look at
the outputs
here. Okay. Children's 6 to 12. Secure,
easy to
use. Invisible, waterproof. How? How?
Here's an interesting question. How will
it be represented if it's
invisible? Children's resiliency, water
resistance, security features, security
features,
digitalization, digitalization.
Okay. D and C water. That's kind of cool
cuz it's waterproof. That makes sense.
Okay. Okay. Imagine a traveling magic
show. I'm not sure we're going to work
with this design firm again, but it at
least at least it looks kind of
cool. Maybe the whole thing is it's like
it's invisible.
Awesome. School programs abstract. Okay.
Um so example
nine is uh again a useful pattern for
those who are keeping school of using
LLM calls to output structured basically
as a transformer as as they as they are
between natural language or structured
information and some kind of output that
you know what kind of output you're
going to get and then you can use that
as an input to some kind of basing
inference or explicit probabilistic
model. That's super useful. Tons of ways
to use that. And then in
eight is this other pattern of just
using sequences of
[Music]
uh sequences of orchestrated. Let's look
at the Stealth Kids Crypto Wallet
report.
So this was the the designing that
invisible waterproof wallet. So here was
the orchestration pattern and in this
situation the orchestration patterns
fixed within the example but you can
imagine creating a situation where it's
dynamic. So let's just try that.
say the
functionalities of these two. Let's just
focus on just the LLM
orchestration of of
of this example. Write a new example 10.
where there is a
config at the top.
So
that the user inputs natural
language for what kind
of
organization
flow they want to
see. We'll see if we can oneshot this.
This might be a few steps.
and first M LM
call
assesses that and
returns whatever
structured format you need so that that
organizational flow can be
implemented using the approach
Similarly with
all
intermediates saved and
the comprehensive org
chart HTML
visualization with the org chart
as prepared after that special first
up.
Then take in
a prompt from second part of the config
block another
variable for what custom or
C. Okay.
Let's look at caucusism
and let's flip that
shuffle.
Okay. Due to the size of the margin, it
will be left as an exercise for the
reader to learn more about what John Ash
is up to, what toxicism is about. Medium
is a good place to see his work. I'm
just going to see if copying this one
glossery document is enough
to make some kind of cool
example. So, making a new
folder
sizer. Let me see if there's any other
blog post.
Let's just try it with just the
wash.
Okay. So that's 10.
in this
folder templating off of
the
functional
eight. Write
a creative, relevant,
useful implementation of the
cognitism
concept. Make
it very relevant
and flexible and with
focus visualizations and animations.
Start with
the
CS
background. If you want to make a Python
file in the folder or
more analysis and
visualization and animation, please do
so. Okay. All right. So here comes 10
for dynamic board generator. And then in
the third of the three possible shots
that are interesting, let's look at what
we could do
for
that. Okay. I don't see where the
actual document
is. Okay. Constitutions of web 3 might
be a good one. So this is a work by Seth
Bray and Josh
Tan and I know they have a GitHub
rep. All right.
So here
they
curated some constitutions from
different dows and different
groups. So just as an example, let's if
if somebody wants to pick a uh
DAO, let's do the DA. Let's do Lex D and
say we'll have a good legal
constitution,
right? I'm going to do something pretty
similar. Examples, new
folder,
lex
file, let's style on
state. All right.
Now I'm going to use the same prompt
with
box templating off of eight. Write a
creative useful implementation
of how lifestyle
works. All
right. So we got cognacism plug here.
Lex down
here. All right. In terms of tool
use,
cursor
49.6 mainly using claw 3.7 sonnet.
Uh, I'm also using Gemini 2.5 a little
bit. There's some things where it's
doing well, but there is a few other
times where it was just
acting
up. Using Obsidian for the
markdowns. I'll push a GitHub update.
Let's see if there's any other Madag
project that we can
go. All right. Do something with
contact. All right. All those are
playing. We'll prepare prepare the
fields. We're
call home.
I'm just going to copy just control a
just
contact
website put in just a few unstructured
pieces of information.
And I'm
walking All
right. At the bottom
there. So obviously this information can
be structured better just to show that
perhaps it doesn't even
matter. Okay. Getting some errors with
calling
tools. We'll see if that works itself
out. Otherwise, it might just be trying
to do too much in one
bite. Okay. At this point, I will uh
while these slowly
turn, I will mention that there's
different ways to support the work. You
could donate at donate.active active
inference.institute. You could get
involved with the open- source
development. You could use this and
reference it. You could fork it and
develop it or contribute to the main
repo. Why
not? We will be having a upcoming series
on multi- aent systems design starting
next week and that will be a one month
design phase about
uh open to all people who want to
participate at the institute. no
specific
background. The meetings are going to be
at 16 UTC on Tuesday and 19 UTC on
Wednesdays and it's going to be first a
design phase of one month to spec out
like what kind of a multi-agent system
are you interested to be developing? Uh
what kinds of agents, what kinds of
information environments, what kinds of
flows, all those types of questions. And
then in June, we're going to move it
into an implementation phase. So, as
kind of shown here, it's easy to get a
sloppy design and implementation with
basically just kind of natural language
prompting or just
using. Um, but I think over the coming
month we're going to have a lot of
really exciting ways to work at that
specification level and then have strong
ways to go from that specification to a
high
reliability very well implemented
system.
So, I would uh encourage anyone who's
kind of peaked by this stream to get
involved that way or if it's after then
just probably still all
good.
Um, yep. Getting a lot of errors with me
calling the edit file, but at least
sometimes it's getting
through. It's just having to do it in
shorter sections.
Um, one more piece that doesn't require
the LLM. This is
a paper that I came
across, notation as a tool of thought by
Iverson from IBM
research. So, a few few quotes here. By
relieving the brain of all unnecessary
work, a good notation sets it free to
concentrate on more advanced problems
and in effect increases the mental power
of the race. A
non and the quantity of being compressed
into a small space by algebraic signs is
another circumstance that facilitates
the reasonings we are accustomed to
carry on by their date. How
relevant. And this uh
paper goes into some pretty exciting
directions discussing
notation and about ways to have
[Music]
information compression and operations
through notation.
So kind of like girdles
orbach a notation scheme is developed
like loop and loop and it's used to
carry out a few different kinds of
things
like imaginary ideas. But now we can
make these notation systems that are
just able to blur the line between the
symbolic and the probabilistic.
And uh some of these things would take a
long time to understand manually but it
would be possible to put this into an
LM and uh develop
implementations based upon that. Like
this would be literally like learning a
whole new language.
But we could
just put it in a file and say okay given
that this is the language that we speak
let's let's just see what
happens
notation. This is going to be
called tool uh dot
notation. Okay. All
right. Run
the dynamic or generator and fix it if
anything
errors.
Okay, in
place now in
place. Let's see if the dynamic
generator works for 10.
So, of course, this is all happening
real time, unscripted. Neither I nor the
machine. So, it's more of an experiment
to
see will it
work,
right?
available in
notation here. I'll use the control K to
use an
inline keeping all the
information
exactly structured this
perfectly and we could pick a different
model. We could use
04.04 04 mini is also pretty
useful. Awesome
though. It's just a little
bit
slow in this document.
write up a bunch of well
annotated examples of using this
notation guys on using
it in
different
places. All
right. All right. But once it gets
started, then it will then it starts
to fix some of
that. Okay.
Yeah, several errors in that first
draft, but now it is going to at least
continue to
go.
Okay. I don't know why we did this.
Yep. All the levels are a little slow,
right? They are getting the job
done. Let's try something
different. Nice.
takes a few
sometimes, but yeah, it could be
faster but at higher LLM cost. Okay,
here we go. So, Gemini coming through.
All right. So,
structured.
Wow.
Okay. Using the control K in line.
All
right. Something
happened. Okay. How do you
use? So more examples just sort of just
to
um kind of respect and uh weed back with
the
past. These are all like kind of
elaborate notation for thinking
approaches. all the stuff GNN AOS
cerebrum all that kind of stuff is
like using function with notation in
these stock
ways. So, agreement
engine, a lot of
similarities. Uh, more of a focus on
agreement. Looks like it hasn't been
updated in a couple of years. Um, but
similar concept, different kinds of
organizational
flows and
[Music]
uh could be could be revisited in our
five era.
community rules.
Similarly, good to be
uh play
Okay. Calling the system
here. This file
is 2030 appropriate.
That's
now
23.
Okay. Visualizations for conscious.
I will take a sip of water. See if
anyone writes any questions or ideas in
the chat and vote that
these finish.
All
right. Lex style is
done.
Run to confirm.
Okay, update the dynamic exam. All
good. Let's switch over to Gemini.
Okay, going faster. Let's just do a
roll
continue and
hands. Okay, maybe it won't happen in
this stream. I don't want to stay on too
long unnecessarily, but I will uh have
to partial function versions
stop. Ah, and
then I'll get
here.
Okay, maybe there
actually.
Okay, it's the epistemic slot machine.
It's like one more. So
close. Push an
update. Oh, look at the
chat update.
LS added to the
list. Okay. All right. Maybe we will get
there. That's always part of the
company.
ignore and
continue. That's something's happening
there. Something is happening
here. Okay. All
right. We could
not. All right.
Awesome. All
right.
Incredible. Actually
incredible. All right. Let's let's do a
different organizational topology just
to confirm the
value. Let's now
run. Here we go. So dynamic or
generate. All right.
So that
was okay. Organization description
organization
task.
We
are updating this to be an
organization that is literally shaped
like a skyscraper.
It is like a skyscrap shaped like a
lollipop
with a bunch
of vertically nested
layers and on the top layer it is hub
and spoke with six
connections. The task uh for the
organization is
actually
appropriately to produce
lollipops. I modified the
quantity. run it again. All right, we'll
see if it actually got there.
Okay,
Lexile is working.
Never
mind. Come
on. Initialization.
Okay.
Okay. Proposals visualized it. So,
um it is hanging here. Fix that and run
it again.
You changing please and not
again. All right, let's look at the
second dynamic or see if we got the
lollipop code.
Who represents the lollipop
guild of of the lollipop for the
lollipop? They succeeded. Fantastic.
Okay. Okay. I wouldn't say that's
exactly
it,
but pretty awesome
nonetheless. Let's just see if we can
get the palm attack going.
in
chat. I'm going to call
Ter
of use and elaborate on that. So it is a
new
example
comprehensively
representing home
tech and organizational
ergonomics
positional. Okay, let's improve it.
Please summarize exactly what to do.
Okay, copy that.
Okay, Tucker, thank you for your
messages. Yes, using cases.
[Music]
Absolutely. Let's do
that.
Okay, we'll do that
as language.
case. organizational
case comprehensively write
up and
obsidian
late documents about how
the
linguistic concept
of
case applies to loyalty agents
and multi- organizational unit
operations make it
incredible and relevant
and all right
[Music]
Yep. Everybody wants to talk about
organizational grammar, but how many
want to talk about linguistic peace?
Looks
great. Could use cerebrum. Of
course, it
looks pretty still
right there.
It looks like it's installed
here. Assess and improve it and re run
Okay, let's see if
it looks good.
Yeah, but if anybody in these last few
minutes has any
uh comment they want read on stream or
just an idea.
Okay. Okay. Lex now is running.
[Music]
Oh, nice.
Just going to leave that one there
because it's going too deep into the
core
mode and we'll let these play out. I'll
just give another minute if anybody
wants
to make a comment or question.
The total cost of the
API credits to OpenAI was about
$4 for for everything today.
could have been could have been cheaper
probably a few different ways,
but all of the work to the cursor was of
course a lot more than that yet
probably much
cheaper. Awesome.
That's now
Maybe it's generating a very long
file. Okay. Oh, there it
is. Let's see if we can get it.
Okay. In closing, let's
do in
docs dialogues.
We'll do move on
first.
$4 true in the chat. $4 API
cost for all of these examples that I'm
running. So
like many dozens including a lot of the
image generation which is probably takes
up a large
amount here right a synoptic
panoptic all good all
[Music]
beautiful all
truthful truly hilarious who's on First
style
Dialogue
regarding all the
information
in
examples down still
Little
Okay, I'm going to call it there,
but as soon as the burst comes through,
All
right. See that? We'll just push the
last
update. Finishing the
stream. And then we'll look at the
dialogue
on
docs
dialogues. Okay, there it is.
All right. Hope this was
uh useful for some, interesting for
some. It's definitely been fun to work
on, and I'm appreciate if you've watched
this far and attended to it. It's uh
pretty fun. So, looking forward to
people's comments and contacting me and
however. All right, till next time.